# Zach Cohen

User Experience Researcher & Designer I zach-cohen.com

My background and work experience are focused on how we interact with the world around us. Through design and research, I am mindful of the entire lifecycle of a product and its business impact. My goal is to help improve systems for groups working in the life sciences and leverage artificial intelligence for precision health and medicine solutions.

# Experience

# **Bentley University User Experience Center**

Research and Design Associate | 2021 - 2022

- Consulted with clients such as Boston Scientific, Ginkgo Bioworks, and Custom Medical.
- Developed and moderated usability tests and interviews.
- Qualitative and quantitative data analysis, insight synthesis, presentation of findings and recommendations.

### Integrate Inc.

Product Designer | 2019 - 2021

- Established a design system guild to guide best practices and overall progression.
- Partnered with product management to conduct discovery and define software features.
- Led design and product-informed strategy for several product development teams.
- Prototyped, user tested, and collaborated with engineering to implement and ship designs.
- Developed user research initiatives to improve integration of research into the product development process.

#### InEight

Interaction Designer (Contract) | 2018 - 2019

- Translated design vision established through research to update legacy product.
- Worked closely with product and development teams to add and refine product features.
- Led user experience optimization alongside key stakeholders and product management.

#### **Nucleus Marketing Lab**

User Researcher (Contract) | 2018 - 2018

- Helped recognize user behavior and re-frame product development goals through qualitative and quantitative research and analysis.
- Used accumulated data to help provide brand strategy insight for both regional and national companies.

#### Education

## **Bentley University**

M.S. – Human Factors in Information Design Expected Graduation 2022

#### Designlab

Certificate - User Experience Design Graduated 2018

#### **Woodbury University**

B.A. – Interdisciplinary Studies (Psychology and Interior Architecture Emphases)

Graduated 2017

## Skills

Qualitative and Quantitative Research

**Usability Testing** 

High Fidelity Prototyping

User Interface Design

Information Architecture

# Software and applications

<u>Design</u>

Figma HTML Adobe XD CSS

Sketch JavaScript
InVision GitHub
Framer Mural

Research

Dovetail Qualtrics

Pendo Survey Monkey

Statistical Analysis R

## **Topics of Interest**

Healthcare/Personal Health AI/ML

Precision Health/Medicine Data Ethics